Shane O Halloran

Email: ohalloran.shane@gmail.com | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/shaneohalloranbis/ | Website: shaneohalloran.com

Profile

I completed my degree in Business Information Systems at University College Cork having achieved a First Class Honours. I am a hardworking, motivated and reliable person. I have gained strong communication, organisational and time-management skills from my previous work experiences including a six-month internship in New York and over one year working for a software development startup in the Pharma industry.

Work Experience

Business Analyst: EviView Limited | Cork, Ireland

December 2020 - June 2022

- Lead multiple software projects from requirements gathering through to development, implementation and technical support for multinational pharmaceutical and biotechnology companies.
- Acted as a SME liaison between the customer and the internal IT delivery project team. Outlined expected timelines and important milestones during the development life cycle.
- Kept business management up to date with the status of projects through the stages of design, development, testing and release.
- Translate client business needs into software requirements used to create concise, understandable user stories and requirements documentation.
- · Facilitated solution reviews and feedback sessions with clients to ensure alignment with expectations.
- · Created interactive software mockups using Google DevTools and product design web applications.
- Managed employee training for all new Junior Business Analyst recruits and offered continuous advice, guidance and mentorship on duties and best practices.
- · Hosted Training workshops for new software releases and provided ongoing support to existing clients.

Web Production Intern: Northwell Health (Marketing and Communications) | New York, USAMarch 2019 - August 2019

- · Updated all Northwell Health websites using their Drupal Content Management System.
- · Created production schedules outlining expected completion dates for various projects.
- · Collaborated with other members of the Digital Strategy team including web developers, UX designers and QA testers. Wrote retrieval and store *SQL* queries for the database of a dynamic web application.
- · Created training documentation to improve the onboarding process for future interns.

Education

BSc Business Information Systems - University College Cork, Ireland

2016 - 2020

- · Achieved a 1.1 First Class Honours Degree.
- Received IIBA Academic Certificate in Business Analysis after completing courses related to IS Development Methods and Software Quality.
- · Studied modules related to User Interaction/Design, Programming, Accounting and Business Analysis.

Skills

Technical: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL, Java, Video Editing and Microsoft Suite.

Analytical: Strategic Thinking, Problem Solving and Data Analysis. **Personal:** Creative, Team Oriented and Excellent Communicator.